

MILES ABBASON

in miles-abbason

▼ miles.abbason@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a software engineer with experience developing serverless, resilient, and efficient cloud applications.

I recently built Seymour, an open-source active monitoring solution for testing API endpoints that is deployed to AWS. Prior to this I founded and grew businesses in the foodservice space, one of which was a franchise across 14 states.

Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer

Seymour (seymour-active-monitoring.github.io) @

2022 - present

Seymour is an open-source globally distributed active monitoring solution deployed to AWS that specializes in synthetic API testing.

- Architected and constructed a globally distributed, parallel API test approach using AWS Lambda, EventBridge, SNS, SQS, Elastic Beanstalk, and RDS to simulate HTTP requests to API endpoints and compare responses against test assertions
- Developed the full stack application using Node.js, PostgreSQL, React, Tailwind CSS, and AWS cloud computing services
- Implemented a notification system that triggers messages via email, Slack, or Discord in the event of a failed test
- Reduced system load by leveraging custom message attributes with AWS SNS topic subscription filtering
- Built full system multi-region automated deployment of Seymour Amazon resources by utilizing AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) to implement Amazon CloudFormation
- Bypassed CDK deployment limitations by employing AWS SDK at runtime to connect resources across different regions
- Authored comprehensive technical case study, readable at: seymour-active-monitoring.github.io/case-study
- · Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers distributed across the US and Europe

Full Stack Web Developer

Launch School Experience

2021 - present

- Developed open-source software w/ technologies such as Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Docker, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS
- Trelloha: Trello-inspired Kanban board for project management built with Node.js, Express, React, Redux, and MongoDB
- Snaggl: RequestBin-like tool for webhooks. Built w/ Node.js, RESTful Express API, React, PostgreSQL

Trading Systems Developer

Self-employed, Crucis Capital

2018 - present

- Created long/short hybrid swing trading program in C# for the NinjaTrader ecosystem
- · Authored 20+ financial market indicators and short-term automated trading strategies

Co-Founder

Self-employed, Pelican's SnoBalls

2011 - 2018

- Orchestrated company growth from 85 franchisees to 176 and into 7 new states over a two-year span
- Developed both franchise and business legal strategy from inception for franchise system in 14 states
- Established financial infrastructure, processes, and controls from inception for 2 separate legal entities
- Launched a nationwide digital and print rebranding campaign for 150+ locations
- Created franchise core-process documentation by developing a comprehensive owner's manual
- Trained 100+ employees and/or franchisees in product, franchise, or business operations
- Founder and Operator: Early-stage franchisee with 2 locations in Durham, NC

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

Cloud

Other Technologies

JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, Handlebars, Go, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, C# (prior experience) AWS: Lambda, SQS, SNS, EventBridge, IAM, RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, Cloud Development Kit (CDK) DigitalOcean (Droplets), Heroku HTTP, REST APIs, Git/GitHub, MVC, Event-Driven Architecture, Docker, Adobe Suite, Linux, Webhooks, SSH, Nginx

Education

Software Engineering & Full Stack Web Development

Launch School @

2021 - 2022

BA Graphic Design, Cum Laude

California State University East Bay

2007 - 2009